servesharp.net 2015-03-19

# ServeSharp

## ServeSharp Exchange Privacy Policy

Please read this policy to understand how ServeSharp collects and uses information to operate its online exchange. The online advertising exchange is operated by ServeSharp.

This policy explains how our ServeSharp Ad Server technology powers our advertising exchange. In particular, this policy explains the data collected both within our advertising exchange and collected on our website. This policy also explains what choices you have regarding the use and sharing of your information within the online advertising exchange.

Details

ServeSharp runs an online advertising exchange for our clients that enables them to buy and sell ad space on websites for online advertising. Our clients are businesses engaged in Internet advertising - advertisers, agencies, publishers, ad networks and other technology providers. Our ServeSharp Ad Server technology powers this online exchange. When ad space on a website is sold, usually to an advertiser, agency or ad network by a publisher or other ad network, the ServeSharp Ad Server technology fulfills the transaction by delivering the ad to that publisher's site. Generally, an Internet user's computer comes into contact with ServeSharp when a user visits a website whose publisher utilizes the ServeSharp Ad Server technology, or views an ad that has been served by ServeSharp Ad Server. The ads sent by the ServeSharp Ad Server technology are sent from the domain ads.servesharp.net and through client domains that forward ads and ad requests to and from ads.servesharp.net.

Types of information we collect and how we use it

ServeSharp is a technology provider for our clients. As a technology provider, we contractually prohibit our clients from sending personally identifiable information to the ServeSharp Ad Server technology and require our clients to post privacy policies that comply with applicable laws, rules and regulations.

Before the ServeSharp Ad Server technology delivers an ad, the technology uses information collected from several sources to decide the best ad to display. The information used helps the technology infer the context in which the ad will appear resulting in a more relevant ad. This section describes the technologies used on our clients' websites to help deliver the most relevant ad to you:

Cookies are small text files that are stored within a browser. They are accessed and recorded by the web site visited and by the companies that show ads on that site to enable them to "recognize" the same browser or user. They are used as part of the ad serving process and also help us collect information about a user's online interactions. The ServeSharp Ad Server cookie helps us maintain a list of ads previously delivered by the ServeSharp Ad Server technology. The cookie also stores the number of times the same ad was delivered, the number of times you have clicked on an ad served by our technology, and the number of times you have possibly engaged in a business transaction on the advertiser's website.

When an ad is served on one of our client's websites, ServeSharp's ServeSharp Ad Server technology collects non-personally identifiable information such as the date and time of your visit to our client's website, your IP address, the type of browser you are using, and the web page address that you are visiting. This information helps our technology infer the context in which the ad will appear. This information is saved in a log file and kept by ServeSharp for auditing and fraud detection purposes.

The ServeSharp Ad Server technology responds to requests from ad tags placed on the website you are visiting. Ad tags provide ServeSharp with information to determine the size and location of the ad. In some cases, websites can also provide information about you, such as non-personally identifiable demographic information.

The ServeSharp Ad Server technology uses web beacons (also known as clear GIFs or 1x1 pixels). A web beacon serves a tiny graphic placed on a web site that is not visible to the user. We allow our clients to use web beacons to measure campaign effectiveness and to optimize campaign performance. For example, if you click through an ad to the advertiser's website, a web beacon on the advertiser's website can report to the ServeSharp Ad Server servers what pages within the advertiser's site that user has visited. The advertiser can then utilize this information to measure the effectiveness of their campaign and provide more relevant advertising. Our technology also uses pixels to allow our clients to create or identify consumer segments and select the appropriate ad based on the segment.

The ServeSharp Ad Server technology collects and stores aggregated ad delivery reporting data. This data is used to provide our clients with campaign reporting and used for billing purposes. A typical report includes information about the ads delivered, including the date and time of ad delivery, the websites on which the ads were shown, and statistics on user response. A report also includes statistics about browser types, date and time of ad delivery, and inferred geography (the IP Address for the web browser is used to approximate, general geographic location).

ServeSharp only collects non-personally identifiable information, including demographic information (such as city or state) and web site activity information.

Transparency, Choice and Opt-Out

The ServeSharp Ad Server technology does not collect any personally identifiable information about you during the ad delivery process. Accordingly, ServeSharp is unable to provide access to or the ability to change information stored by our technology.

The ServeSharp Ad Server technology uses cookies for ad selection in order to enhance ad effectiveness. ServeSharp believes that cookies enhance your web experience in a number of ways such as by limiting the frequency of how often we display certain ads and increasing ad relevancy. ServeSharp offers consumers the ability to opt out from our use of data associated with the ServeSharp Ad Server cookie to deliver relevant ads. You can opt out here. By opting out, ServeSharp Ad Server will place an opt-out cookie on your computer that will prevent our technology from targeting ads based on your interest.

Because cookies are browser specific, if you use more than one browser on your computer, you will need to opt-out of the ServeSharp Ad Server cookie on the other browser(s) in order to opt-out completely. Please note that you will need to opt out of the ServeSharp Ad Server cookie again if you buy a new computer, upgrade or change the browser on your existing computer, or delete the ServeSharp Ad Server opt-out cookie.

Information Sharing and Disclosure

ServeSharp may provide copies of log files to advertisers, clients and certain partners relating to the specific transactions they are a party to. These files contain information that allows clients to analyze the effectiveness and performance of their advertising campaign. Our clients also have the ability to use any or all of the information collected in connection with our services for their own purposes. The information provided to our clients does not contain personally identifiable information about you. In cases where ServeSharp provides information to our clients, our clients are obligated to use the information they receive in compliance with applicable laws and regulations.

ServeSharp may share the information it collects with selected partners, vendors, agents or others who work on our behalf, in order to provide products or services you've requested, or when we have your permission. ServeSharp may share information about you if ServeSharp is acquired by or merged with another company.

ServeSharp may also share information in the event that we are asked to respond to subpoenas, court orders, or legal process, or to establish or exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims, or as otherwise permitted by law.

ServeSharp may update this policy from time to time. Please check this privacy policy for updates.

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us at the following: [support@servesharp.com](mailto:support@servesharp.com)
